[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
oh what's up y'all welcome to the
junkyard love podcast
i'm happy you're here it's me your host
squidward
tentacles today before we get rolling
onto the podcast
with trevor may i just want to drop a
quick little knowledge tip a quick
little
thing you may not have been thinking
about today and now you are
and that's posture posture and
confidence man when you walk out when
you leave your house we're all in
quarantine we're all in cove
at times we haven't been able to leave
our house as much maybe we're slumped
over our shoulders are forward a little
bit more
we got our hoodie on we're comfy we're
mumbling more we're looking down on our
devices more
we're all doing it it's all right but
let's just think about when we leave our
house what's our posture like
can we put our chest out can we pull
like an imaginary string from the top of
our head
can we put our shoulders back serotonin
is released in our bodies when we
actively control our posture
for more information on serotonin and
confidence and posture look up jordan
peterson's talks about lobsters
it's wonderful i just want to make sure
you guys are thinking about those sort
of sort of things so what's your posture
right now are you slumping
are you you got that old text neck right
now stretch out your neck
move it around you know uh be ready for
showing up in your life as your best
charismatic self
build yourself up with your own ability
to bring awareness
to your posture
it's important all right let's get going
trevor may
jake ryan's here we go
get it going ladies and gentlemen
welcome to
the junkyard love podcast i am here with
trevor may trevor may thanks for being
here man
thanks for having me dude yeah so
it's a it's cool that we we get to
reconnect we were just kind of briefly
talking before this
uh mentioning the dj world
so we we met in high school but we
actually dj'd together people may not
know that you used to be a dj
i did that was the that was the pre you
know
streaming trevor uh that was the thing i
was obsessed with before
i got into what i'm currently into right
yeah do you still ever do any any djing
at all anymore
i do a little bit um just for fun i i so
my big purchase
um after i got to the major leagues it
was i always told myself i'd get like
one big thing is get called up it's a
major milestone in your life
and then uh you're up for a bit and
you're obviously your pay goes way way
up
that's the dream and you're just uh i
always
i was was encouraged to pay find one
thing that you've like always wanted to
get but it was always just like kind of
a
like it wasn't necessary but it was like
something you really wanted to have
um and yeah nothing that's like a you
know 100 000
car but like something cool so i was
like i want i want some cddj's so
i have uh some nexus's 2000s that i
i'm pretty sure still the industry
standard um the nice thing is i think
they're worth more now than they were
then but uh
yeah i got them there in the garage and
pull them out every couple months and go
i was gonna start doing some live
streams with uh
just like doing some dj mixes taking
making a day and like starting with an
hour and like just playing all my
favorite music because i have like a
spotify playlist a bunch of people
follow so
basically just showing off the new week
stuff and it turns out twitch is now
dmca
music so hard that we can't play music
at all
yeah i heard about that i got the email
that was explaining like here's what's
going on
yeah it sucks because twitch was kind of
like the last
bastion yeah it's so hard to play music
that's
uh not copyrighted and not get flagged
uh which is weird because now like
beatport because beatport and like
insomnia and all the all the big big big
like kind of
music music players in the music space
spinning
they've all like they would do they were
doing tons of live shows and stuff and
like a lot like having
artists on one during quarantine um and
now they're just having to jump through
all even though like a lot of the music
they own
they just gotta jump through hoops you
gotta turn off the mca on their own
stuff like it's becoming a huge huge
problem so they can get
like so they can use it later for like
social media and stuff so like
it just could turn that upside down
which is hilarious because it's kind of
they're doing
but right yeah they're like let's make
sure we're getting paid but we can't get
paid
we but we got to make sure we're not
getting paid for the stuff that we're
using already you know like
yeah it's it's just it's kind of goofy
but um it's a weird
it's like sewing your own pocket [__] a
little bit yeah
yeah uh it's it's i'm kind of what do
you think it's gonna
i mean we're not just gonna continue to
go down this to where it's like all we
can play in our videos and stuff on
on twitch and live streams and even when
it comes to instagram facebook which is
like more intense with the takedowns
yeah there's got to be some sort of
algorithm or something that somebody's
employing that is
creating something where it like hears
you know it shazams it hears it
and it's like i'm going to let you play
it but i'm just going to make sure like
you know
young thug gets his two cents and then
his record label gets there three cents
like it just distributes i feel like
eventually we're going there
yeah i think that's that's probably the
solution um or something along those
lines
uh we were actually talking about this
on my own podcast we had a uh
we had like a gaming lawyer he works
with a lot of uh
content creators to make sure they're
trademarked and protected and
going over contracts and stuff because
that's becoming a huge market uh
and he was he explained it in depth he's
like i think a really interesting
opportunity is gonna be a lot of
creators like partnering with
um music labels and stuff to like almost
almost it's like a sponsorship
relationship but like
they allow you to use their stuff you
get you get you get white listed and
then
kind of streamlining that white list a
system so that like there's just more
so because in reality they do want this
is an archaic law that they can enforce
and there's only there's only a few big
players really enforcing it and then a
lot of other ones don't really care
but like they're but it's but it's
applying to everybody
so like because these huge
uh labels want don't want the mute like
drake's label for example doesn't want
his music played
like all these other ones that are like
mid-tier labels or whatever that liked
all the exposure kind of like getting
your song on tick-tock
like blows it up it's it's streaming
it's an opportunity for people to hear
your stuff that might not
they might not hear otherwise those
people are getting
are losing the ability to play music
because they're just not gonna play any
music they're not gonna take the chance
so like so now like i know that t-pain
for example is huge on
twitch he's he's he's got people on his
label making royalty-free stuff just for
fun like just stuff they had on the side
he's like let's put this all out
and let people think so like these
platforms are popping up left right
center where people like
putting up as much copyright stuff as
possible stuff they made themselves
now there's like smaller artists on
twitch that are literally just making
music for people to play on streams so
there's becoming this huge
market for it um and then i think the
bigger players when that turns into
money when they can figure out a way to
monetize that well in the live streaming
space
then it'll just then it'll just kind of
like that law will just kind of be
they'll change it yeah a thing of the
past that we've moved
moved through that's actually a savage
move that t-pain is just having his boys
just make music for what's actually
going on he's huge on twitch too like in
the last six months what does he play
like does he he he's been doing like
music like crazy like literally
producing
an album what he's like i think he's
doing a full album where it's all live
on twitch which is super cool
um but he he played i mean he he played
overwatch like when i got started in
2016. like
he's been on longer than me probably um
and uh but yeah he plays games every
once while but it's mostly like just
like
he has a show like uh like a kind of a
talk show type thing where he brings on
streamers and they like play a game
together and they hang out
and uh he's got people in like a stream
team that are that are
uh all kind of different kinds of
personalities too and then he's got a
bunch of artists you know on his own
label that are doing
various things and he brings them in so
it's like his way of it's the way he
communicates now
which is super super amazing too because
you know he's been around for
twenty years he's been around we we
probably
like dance battled and at proms to
his jams yeah you know like even he was
even been around for
even in 2008 when i was a senior he had
been or he had been around for a while
so yeah like early 2000's when he broke
on the scene
i remember i saw i saw a thing it was a
couple years ago like he had kind of
faded away you
hadn't really heard his name for a few
years and then uh
he came out with something that was just
him slaying with no auto-tune like his
voice is just
super exciting he's great but uh it was
funny because there was a little
transition
of people being like wait he can sing
without auto-tune because a lot of
people don't really like understand what
auto-tune is it's just a
just a tool it's like a synthesizer for
your voice right yeah
yeah yeah and especially when you make
kind of like i don't know like pop
hip-hop like he did
like attituding your voice just made it
like fit really well in the genre so
like
it's just the way he sang hooks you need
the hook to be really catchy
and obviously just helped it's just like
a bunch of rappers use auto-tune now
because they're singing their own hooks
and they can't really sings but they
want it to be hooky still so they're
so like they're doing on it too and it
gives them their like flair like travis
scott and
all those guys yeah no and it sounds
tight i've seen a couple of videos of uh
like they're singing their song and then
they kind of break like they're yelling
at someone in the crowd
and it's just them yelling in in auto
tune
have you seen them no i haven't but that
sounds like something i would enjoy
yeah um also i was going to mention so i
think
uh i know logic is big in the streaming
world
and i know there was a thing uh on
fortnight i believe it was with
there was one with marshmallow and one
with travis scott where they like had a
concert
on on twitch do you know about that yes
i was i was at li
i went i still played the game a lot
when marshmallow did his it was probably
the most
it was groundbreaking um in terms of so
cool dude
yeah the world the world is very much at
least in the world
world of entertainment and content uh
live like access to somebody
like famous is like like you saw it with
when ninja played with drake
and that guy was like wait we're
listening to drake's like speak live
like through um
like that was like it's just not
something he does like everything's kind
of like
planned it felt very unplanned like he's
like hey let's play and ninja was like
okay and it was just huge 700 000
viewers
um and then marshmallow doing a live
show and everyone got on the game at the
same time you knew there was millions of
people
there with you so it was like going to a
show and being like like you know how
you look around you're like
there's 15 000 people here this is
freaking awesome like that's
you're sharing something with that many
people like it felt like that i mean
it's something that it was just a huge
undertaking to do as a game developer
and then the travis scott one was in
terms of like production like so
marshmallows was really cool there was
like anti-gravity it was like he got
really big and then
the world disappeared for a bit you're
flying around in space that was cool but
travis scott's was like
like like an acid trip like super like
the cool like you're flying through this
whole story
right and he's like telling it with his
music which was
insane it's just like the player the
player base for me anyway i wasn't
playing the game very much so
i just watched people watching it live
on stream um but
those events created like so many
opportunities for content creators to to
give their reactions to it and then gave
him exposure it's it was just like
unparalleled i think we're in other
games as games coming ebb and flow and
come back and
go it's like the connection to pop
culture is just going to keep getting
stronger and stronger and stronger which
is
super cool you know especially with
covid i mean it's cool
it's cool that we're still able to find
i think that was pre-covered but
it's cool that we're still able to uh
like find new ways of integrating
integrating like just human connection
and find new ways to actually be like
excited and we're you know because we're
not together
but when everybody is watching the same
person live it is this like weird
togetherness it is that vibe that it's
creating it's super cool i wonder
the i mean the future of gaming
i mean it's definitely going to go like
augmented virtual reality i think
yeah what do you think about the future
of gaming like where do you see it
let's say 10 years if things are going
well where would you say gaming is
dude i we're getting to the point where
everything looks so
the the world of uh ready player one
i don't think it's too far away i don't
think that
everything's gonna be done in a virtual
world game that's made maybe not that
full
completion just because people compete
with each other so like there's so many
competing
brands right and there's no way that one
team would take over but they're like
it's crazy the advent of like how
schools being done online needs to be
changed
like people are struggling with how it's
done right now like because it was
happening
thrown away zoom isn't gonna do it but
augmented reality where kids are like
where their entire attention is them
virtually being somewhere
yeah um is gonna be like the necessity
like they're gonna they can't take their
headset off type thing
uh uh they have to be there and be in a
classroom but not actually physically be
there
that's like something that they're it's
just expensive now but when that when
that like
barrier lowers and lowers lowers like
it's 300 bucks to buy a headset not 1200
dollars
um it could be it could turn and then if
you're going to school online
online like that like there's no that's
there's no limit to like the things you
can do in uh
reality at that point so we saw it with
snapchat putting augmented reality in
then
and then everyone's stealing it uh and
that becoming like
interesting and something that captures
attention and then you just if you
go in virtual reality where your entire
world is
now that um um the ability to like learn
and like
trick your br make your brain think that
it's all just
that's what's that's your environment
that's around you it's just easier to
learn that way so
i think school could very easily um some
really progressive schools might already
be doing it
right we don't even know but uh that's
one big thing
uh and then you know games games are
games are kind of just like
hit or miss just because like for
example me i i get motion sickness so
anything that's like
i have to be active and like i'm finding
that guy's moving and shooting them and
stuff like it's just too much like i
can't
because my body doesn't feel what i'm
seeing um and that's
that's that's tough for me um and i'm
not about to take dramamine before i
play games so like
the ability to do games i think is
limited because there's just i mean i
know we're in the minority but there's a
lot of people that like that just
doesn't feel good with
um but yeah i'm just sitting in a chair
like i can sit in a chair and i can just
look around like i'm cool with that
but when when it starts like in the game
when it signa
like when it signals that you're moving
like you you're like wait my legs aren't
actually physically doing anything but
my vision
is going my body just instantly breaks
into a sweat and i'm like
well
it's not registering you moving but your
eyes are it's it's
i don't know how it actually doesn't
make sense physiologically what we just
said
sounds like that's the way it should be
and there's just like 90 of the
world's like nah that's fine i'm like i
don't understand why that's fine
yeah what why aren't you understanding
that you're being tricked right now
yeah it's yeah it's uh i think i lasted
i've done it because
i'm living with tyler daniels now he
does a lot of games and uh
he he had me try two different games one
was pretty chill
but i didn't i don't think i lasted five
minutes and it was just
the act of walking like i wasn't moving
my feet but i'm floating and that got me
and then i tried the new
star wars game and that was cool but
then i'm just like i
like you don't have your your center
like i don't know which side is up or
down
yeah and so i just started feeling like
i was physically upside down spinning
backwards somehow and i was like yep
i'm good on this i'm going to throw up
so but uh i mean dude i think the the
future of all that stuff is going to be
better and more creative than we can
even imagine i was working
last year before covet it was actually i
think about a year ago around this time
i was working um up in fl
up at flc for wadeca
at the maiden bauer in bellevue and uh
one of the guys that i was working with
basically telling me that he had been a
few months prior
it was either amazon or google or one of
these big tech companies
and they were kind of having like the
insiders like the bigwigs of the bigwigs
had this conference basically talking
about the future of
um i don't remember who's amazon or
google one
one of the big companies and uh i think
it was kind of a hush
hush secretive sort of thing but they
were basically talking about how
2035 i guess they're they're going to be
a lot of virtual reality by 2035 like
that's what they're shooting for virtual
augmented so i mean if that's what their
plan is like
we as humans and participants are just
along for the ride
so i think we're going to wally world
yeah there's a lot of that
going on there's a lot of us just being
along for the ride and being tugged and
pulled by
technology which is terrifying but also
inevitable um the way we the way we
have completely uh put like
innovation and tech companies on a
pedestal like that's like the holy grail
like
discovering that next thing right um and
so with this many people going for that
and like specializing in that
and thinking in that way we're just it's
just the way it's gonna go man like
without even from how we're marketed to
on social media
um and these bubbles that everyone's
like oh you're stuck in your own echo
chamber well you know what
the platform itself is actually creating
that more than anything uh more than
even you
yes uh which is that's terrifying i i
don't know if
you know a lot about that but that's
absolutely horrifying um
and uh and now there's gonna be
augmented reality and
and all this stuff and like how how what
we're seeing is being controlled by
maybe other people is something to
constantly be aware of
yeah we're the data now like we're being
sold um the good example is kind of like
tick tock like
doritos says hey do a dance and you'll
get featured with all these views and
all these
these likes and watches and whatever and
then you now have like
your young children working for doritos
they're advertising for doritos by doing
a dance or
um have you watched the social dilemma
i've talked about that a couple times
exactly what i'm talking about yeah yeah
it's it did it it blew my mind i've
actually
i i watch a lot of content from tristan
harris
who's one of the main guys in that um
the last two years i've watched like all
of us
all these podcast interviews and it's
like
sometimes when i when i talk about it i
have this like terror
where i'm just like is this is everybody
not taking this serious because this
seems like the biggest deal ever
social media is changing what we do and
controlling
everything on purpose yeah yeah on
purpose like that's the thing like
that's the distinction i i need to tell
i make sure that people know i'm like
guys of course it changes like we change
like i'll look for opportunities in real
life that are capturable
because i create content that's like a
way you think when you create content
that's that's changed me that's social
media changing me but
and that's just kind of like i feel like
that's growth and that's
you know that's something once you're
aware of it you can choose to do it or
not
um as much up to a certain point but
when people
are advertising that they can change
people's behavior like if you're close
to being the archetype of something they
can
nudge you into that archetype that's
that's terrifying because that
takes the control from you or or or your
conscious
if you're not conscious of something
that's like our biggest every problem
we've ever had as a human race is
because we unconsciously do stuff
like everything from from from racism to
like everything it's just it's always
deep seated and like we're doing things
we don't realize
are a bad and that and they are and we
realize and we fix it later like that's
kind of how we are so like when people
can exploit quote unquote
good things or bad things about us and
say hey we can get push them into this
this left uh slant because some that
someone who needs them there
gave us money to do it that's like that
sounds inherently evil to me
uh that sounds like evil empire stuff
that sounds like uh
and and you know there's the social
eleven then i can't remember the name of
it but the one that is actually about
um cambridge analytica like explains the
whole situation that could be that's an
example of the things they talked about
in the social dilemma happening
right the great hack maybe was that one
uh the great hack
yeah it might have been i don't even
because technically it wasn't hacking
but basically the you know cambridge
analytica
in england and if you probably watched
it i'm assuming but um
i think i recall the same one they
worked for the the they had
a bunch of people they weren't cambridge
atletico the time but a lot of people
that were hive in that company were for
obama no a
um and really utilized myspace and
facebook when it was early
and then uh trump hired him in in 16 and
uh they had honed in that behavioral
changing thing and they're like we can
do it and they did
and that's what happened and yeah
someone's like hey
someone in these states was like well
well realized and asked for his data not
anyone else's just like can i have mine
and they're like sure and then
pussyfooted around for six months and
then went bankrupt
and that's kind of how it happened then
they they basically dodged it they knew
they were caught
and then they they destroyed a bunch of
stuff went bankrupt and then just
disappeared
there was no legal actions or anything
and it's this thing that's so
new and so like it it happened so fast
too that we're like we
not only don't have laws to control this
most of us don't even know what's going
on
like it's it's like these old wooden
board rooms
trying to solve virtual reality level
problems exactly
exactly just advanced too much and we
got we got people in congress they're
like uh
i i don't even have a smartphone you're
like yeah
i don't know what to tell you about
they're like so is this about flappy
bird or yeah exactly
exactly like uh i mean one thing
there's a lot of scary stuff when it
comes to social media and just how
quickly technology
has integrated with us i mean we like
think about
a hundred years ago saying hey you have
a flashlight attached to your body at
all times so you'll never
be in the dark again anytime you're lost
and you don't know where you are on the
continent you can pull up
three clicks of a finger and you'll be
able to see where you're at with the pin
drop
oh also any information you want to know
you just look at your magic rectangle
and
it you just ask it what you want to know
and it tells you exactly what you want
to know
i mean that's huge for humanity man
that's a
huge jump yeah yeah it's huge
jump but i i really really just because
we are
going there and there's very little
we're going to do to like
stop we're just going to have to guide
that path
better so it doesn't stray off into
crazy because it's not there's nothing
we can do there's like really there's
nothing we do to like
we're not going away from smartphones
we're not going away from social media
we're not going to we're not going to
go back to email as our like it's just
not going to happen it just simply isn't
when you accept that and you accept that
like maybe
social media doesn't change people the
way that we think it does it doesn't
make people shitty it doesn't make
people like
all this bad stuff happen or good stuff
happen it just exposes people like
um one that when they get feedback for
some of their bad worst desires or best
advice desires they tend to want to do
that stuff more
it's just like when you're a kid and
your parents are saying put the toy down
or pick the toy up
it's time to play it's not time to play
things like that it's the same thing
we're humans we that's the way we learn
so um you know it once you accept it
like hey this
rectangle is going to be and it is a
tool and if i use this tool and people
who are in power
are checking it and making and you can
trust it uh
then you shouldn't be afraid of it so
it's not like a we're not trying to fear
monger we're just saying
of course awareness is important because
then you can
well i'm just not going to go on it as
much or or you're gonna be like i am but
i'm gonna i'm gonna on purpose try to
try to sculpt this thing to be as wide
as
possible and see how i can do it um as
opposed to just like
going down rabbit holes all the time
without any sort of conscious thought
yeah i mean dude i think uh you
mentioned awareness i've listened to a
couple of your other podcasts and you
mentioned awareness a lot and i
definitely want to signal in on that
but i think that's a huge thing is
bringing awareness to what am i doing
and why am i doing it and i think trevor
that you've done
what you're doing very well i i think
you know with moving to
the streaming um all of your online
content
like that's huge i mean i was just
looking just doing a little research and
going through you have just tons of
hours and you've clocked in and you've
really
transitioned very well into this
online content creating thing you want
to talk to me about like
even the beginning stages did you think
you'd have this much momentum
did you consciously make the decision
okay i'm going to go into this streaming
thing because it sells myself
as a brand and then you're able to you
know kind of be a motivator for young
kids you're able to
you know have fun and inspire people
but also enjoy it and make it a business
and yeah
how was that transition um so
i think the the one thing that anyone
that's already in it or was in it before
me um
can also attest to is most people just
started to see
what was all about so like i i had time
my whole thing with video games
especially during the season is i just
i decide i i need when i want to do
something i want to be good at it
so like if i'm going to start something
i just don't like dabble
i like go all in and find something that
i really enjoy
i'm like so my first question i asked is
like how much time can i have devoted to
this
i got hurt at tons of time kate wasn't
living with me she was still
living home in seattle during the season
so like she was coming to visit
like i had tons of time so i was like i
love games let's play games and then
i played games and i was like okay i
want to learn how to play this game
better because i have time and i want to
like be good at it i'm not just going to
be like bad and sit here for hours and
waste time being bad at something i want
to actually become good at it feel like
i'm accomplishing something
uh so then i then i went back like i'd
watched twitch since 20 early 2015 just
off and on
um and i was like all right let's start
watching twitch i just started
discovered some of these big content
creators i was like dude i can do that
like i that's that's my brain like these
guys uh there's got tim the tattman's
become a good friend of mine and his
his best friend paul uh action jackson
who's actually my
my co-host on my other my podcast we're
currently going
um about center around content creation
stuff i met them through gaming
because they're my same age they
graduated in 0-8 they're just from
syracuse
so like i was like then they're best
friends so i was like you two i would
they were on the baseball team like you
know what i mean
like they were uh to put in the contest
they were like uh uh like
hate teeters and colin kelly like you
know
like that best buds like that and i was
friends with colin and tate really well
because we played on the same sports
teams
i would have just been the buddy that
went and played professionally right
that's just what i would have done
but like they're kind of their humor
everything i'm like they're nerds but
they're all they were also athletes i
was a nerd and athlete that's just
that's just the way it is i didn't know
at the time but i was
uh and and so i gravitated towards just
because i like their
the qual their their their style i liked
them as people and all their references
were the same for me
so like i was like i'm part of this
community i became a really huge
big thing in their community and then i
was like i want to do this so once i
decided that
that's what i was like all right make a
computer i'm gonna build it myself i'm
gonna learn all this stuff your way
you're supposed to do it it was just
youtube video youtube video youtube
video youtube video yeah youtube video
and every day just
fed into something else and i was able
to meet them i started going to the
conferences i went to twitchcon i went
to blizzcon i
i i was at the inauguration of the
overwatch league
and they were all there so i like i knew
them from online i met them in person
we hit it off as buds and now we're now
we're friends um
and and it's all about like developing
kind of the the friendships of community
it's all built around community so
i'm a professional athlete i was like
one thing that we don't do well is
provide access to us so i was like this
is checking every box like this whole
thing is like
this makes sense it's where the world's
going uh you can make it a business that
gives me excuse to play lots of video
games which is another perk
right so there's just like there's just
is no downside of this except for
the amount of time it takes but like
yeah it's i'm gonna spend this time on
something that i really enjoy anyways
that's what i do i just lock into my
hobbies uh
and now it's become like if you jobs uh
and i i
dude you know you know me from high
school bro i was i did all the lip syncs
i did like i'm just like entertaining
people
i was on sports teams i always hype
people up like i was just i just kind of
had that was the energy that i that i go
off of i love competing
like right that's all i i could have
i think i could have easily been like a
theater kid just as easily as being an
athlete like just because of the way i
am i i like that
um and i've gravitated gravitated
towards people who are
like singers and actors and stuff just
because i like identify with
that feeling of being on stage and
having people react that's why i dj'd
like it's the same thing it makes
performance yeah yeah i like performing
so uh
that like like even since i noticed this
yesterday even since i've been on twitch
the way that i speak has become so much
clearer and
how quickly i get thoughts out and the
way i can go and explain things has just
improved
tenfold i used to mumble have really low
voice and be a little bit more shy uh
and all that's changed over the last
five years just because i talk in front
of a camera so much
and uh now i do interviews and stuff
people like wow dude you're
like you should do radio i'm like i do a
stream yeah like
40 hours a week radio winner that's
like i do this all the time yeah i'm
like i'm in front of a mic as much as
you guys are in front of a mic so like
yeah
you know i mean this is actually natural
yeah i mean just like anything you
sharpen it you know you get good
you get good at your sport by just
putting your hours in by just putting
the time and that's the same thing i
mean i kind of learned with this podcast
i you know i i was i've been pretty good
at talking to people but you know
having long form conversation is kind of
difficult you know
three hour long podcasts podcast when
you're
losing your train of thought or you
don't know what you're talking about or
blah blah blah
but kind of allowing yourself to just
try it and just keep going
and just keep talking and then sure
enough you'll listen to yourself a year
later and you're actually making sense
and you're not stumbling over
your words and uh not mumbling as much
it's interesting
we live in such a bite-sized world where
everything is just condensed down and
let's see if we can say the shortest
thing and summarize in the shortest way
but but having like the long-form
conversations or or explaining yourself
in a long
sense it's i don't know it's nice it
feels more natural like you kind of shut
off your brain and you just
you just talk you just explore and
that's just who you are and people
gravitate towards that
yeah yeah i i it's it's i you know i
started the podcast and stuff too it's
just been like even days i'm like
if you're gonna ask me an hour i'm tired
and then you're 45 minutes and you're
like
and we're vibing like just because it's
something you really enjoy doing talking
and just letting your stream of
consciousness kind of go that's kind of
our format too a little bit
uh it has been it's just not it's
relaxing it's nice and people like
listening to it because it's relaxing
for them
and and so uh you know audio is a great
medium i'm glad that uh
i've i'm freaking pumped that that you
asked me to be on this i'm pumped you've
been
doing this for so long i mean it's
awesome yeah dude yeah i'm super happy
to have you on here i was
so i was listening you have a you said
you have a newer podcast
um with what was the gentleman's name uh
sims paul
or action jackson is is this like twitch
name action jackson paul yeah because i
was listening to the trevor may podcast
um from i think it was 2018 that you
started that one
and man there's some good stuff on there
too um
but it's it's it's it's cool to see
i don't know because you know i i know
you like you know we weren't like bffs
when we were growing up but i knew you
pretty well
um and you're still you're still the
same guy you're still the same trevor
but listening to you through this
podcast and through you explaining
yourself and you're like trying to help
people out you're like here's what i've
learned
it's it's super inspiring like it's a
it's
just actually seeing now that we're
older seeing the growth of a person
in real time you're like oh wow yeah
you're the same person but you're also
this
just a way better version of yourself it
sounds like you know you're really
leaning into this thing and you're
enjoying your life and you've done very
well at it you know
it's it's been it's crazy to think about
like i
i i'm one of those people that though i
do
like respect like milestones or or
uh like seeing those steps and being
like grateful for like where you've come
from i i tend to downplay like
i just have that mindset and it's kind
of a blessing and a curse that like
you never know you're just it's never
over like you're never you're never
there
you're never gonna get there never
you're never arriving
exactly uh always a work in progress
that's that's uh
uh the ceo of spanx says that all the
time i've always worked in progress
uh i watched your master class um
uh and and so like i tend to be like oh
yeah big leagues that was awesome but
like
now i gotta stay you know like that's
just how i always am so
uh it's really really nice to hear
people have noticed it or
hey man that was really good and that
was inspiring like you made something
good
uh yeah that that for me is a bigger
that's something that i actually like
take in more than
actually like an accomplishment that i
perceived that i have
on my own without you know without
anyone uh uh
else being part of it uh and and so like
what and when when i see other people
um you know for example a buddy i've
made over over the over the years now
jordan fisher i don't know if you know
him but he's he's a singer
songwriter uh he he was in hamilton on
broadway
like the second the second cast um and
he's our
insanely talented guy but he's super in
on twitch and plays lots of video games
really good video games too
um he just recently finished his own
produced
and uh he was a producer and a starred
in a in a
in a movie i think it's a netflix show
amazing and he's 26
so i was like dude that's that's like
that made me so i was like dude i was so
hype
i it's more hype than i've any if
someone said hey you produced a show i'd
be like oh thanks man
but like for him i was like oh this is
awesome like that is the coolest thing
i've
because you know that's like the it's
like the next but
next to like directing and like then
just being your own
like directing and and starring in your
own movies and then having those take
off
beyond that like there's nowhere else
like he's almost at the
you know yeah like you you have an idea
in your head and you make it into
reality
yeah and you're the guy that like did it
yeah you did it you direct you pushed it
there and you guided it that's
freaking that's insane so like i'm
starting to notice
that i'm getting so excited when when
people that that i care about are doing
crazy crazy crazy stuff like uh that
tim the tattman did that thing with fall
guys where it just exploded
over the internet like everyone he could
not win a game and
like it was on espn and like it was like
a live counter of how many games like
play there was a trending hashtag
worldwide number one
trending hashtag this had been tweeted
over a million times
he did it when he won it was just he did
it he did it and it was him winning a
game of fall guys
the memes came out that one where
everyone keeps uh
like uh superimposing like a video and
it's that
at uh that bar in britain where like
they're getting excited
it was a soccer match with like team
england scoring a goal but like
everyone keeps putting the video on to
like line it up with the kid did that
for him that got like
1.5 million views on twitter like huge
exploded everyone knew tim
tam once we could not win this stupid
easy like
arcade game and he was getting so mad it
took him four or five days
of playing for like six hours like it
took 20 hours of the gameplay everyone
else won their first game in like two
hours
every single person in the world and he
just could not and it became this huge
like
pension event when he finally did it i
saw the like
how beautifully that content was created
yeah and he did it and he realized like
how
he was a big streamer for that like he's
he's a huge content creator
that just like launched him right
i saw on his face he's like bro like
i've done some big stuff with my this is
this is like you couldn't do this on
purpose i was like this is so cool and i
was like
in it yeah that's exactly right you
couldn't do this on purpose that's
it speaks to that just like do your work
do your thing you know like i i think
there's a lot of
you know there's a lot of lure to
let's see if i can get noticed let's see
if i can do this thing that's crazy or
one step
above this other person but it's just
when it's
what we really like as humans especially
when we're watching content
is the organic like we want to see
it actually happening to you and then we
can make it this fun camaraderie
community thing where we're all
submitting memes about it and we're all
laughing about it together in our homes
that's super cool yeah and we smell
[__] really easy too
like you can tell one thing like you
yeah i troll tick tock quite a bit dude
it's great great
hilarious it's there's tons of there's
tons of ideas and stuff for other kinds
of ideas but you can tell when like
i surprised my husband with bubba and
it's just staged you can tell
immediately and you're like
dude and it's always a verified account
that can't think of anything to do and i
hate it
and it drives me insane i immediately
but the stuff that you can tell like
naturally wasn't expected to happen uh
and that so like it's i was listening to
a podcast uh
there's these two guys that i just i'm
luckily enough a guy named blake robbins
who um if you're familiar with esports
much at all um
there is a there's a team called 100
thieves in la
nade shot it was the next knicks an ex
cod player he tried to like he stopped
playing he was a world champion he's
he's in his late 20s now so like that's
old in
gaming i mean i'm 31 and that's we're
older
uh and and he was trying to start his
own esports organization
it's kind of like a merch brand kind of
like streetwear and stuff and it's cool
but he didn't really know where to go
didn't have the manpower he's got blake
robbins he
he is a uh um a venture capitalist and
was like
got basically said daniel he worked for
dan gilbert who owns the cavaliers
and dan was like hey you're our resident
young person how do we get into video
games and he's like
well you know this guy nature is trying
to start a thing and he's huge fan of
nature and he's like and he's got a
personal brand but he wants to create a
brand that's timeless
outside of his personal thing he's like
okay cool let's buy a team he's like no
no
we're not gonna buy a team like let's
listen to him like it's beyond
playing professionally whatever so they
built this
100 thieves is exploding it's a content
house it's they have they have
professional teams and
100 thieves merch like sells out in
minutes every single time they do it
like supreme like it's
and it's really really cool street where
i got some stuff my own like it's
joggers and it's like you know
super clean hoodies and stuff and it
represents like you know everyone's
wearing it with their yeezys i don't
wear easies but like
i i get the culture i understand why
that like that's
shoes and clothes are a whole subset
right so if you can get yourself into it
in a gaming way
crazy so they built that so blake
robbins is kind of like he's still on
the board there
he's a young guy he's like in his 20s
and he's helped build this company he's
still there
and he explained told me all about how
did he does a podcast with mr beast on
youtube
i don't know if you know who mr beast is
if you don't you're you should look him
up he's got
20 million he's the dude who's like i
gave away a million dollars
today like or i gave away an entire you
know
car dealership full of but in reality
he's like he's like giving people
ability to do stuff challenges but he's
just like helping people out in reality
like he picks people that can
pick and so he he gave like a kid 40
cars he's like okay
there's one catch you get to keep the
car that you want he goes which one do
you want he was i want this one he was
okay you keep that one
if you can give away the other 39 to 24
hours so he literally called every
person he knew he was like come get a
car
and it was hilarious because some of the
cars were just terrible and some were
awesome
like it was dune buggies there was all
kinds of stuff in there right and it was
an awesome
video i was like this was an awesome
idea and it's a really cool thing and
40 people got free cars yeah but he's
gonna probably make that money off that
video because he got like 20 million
views
so like he's that's his business so his
manager
and blake robbins who built help on they
do a podcast so that was my
that was my long story long they
explained this to you they do a podcast
called creator economics
phenomenal basically they what we're
talking about how this all works they
just explain like an element
of how it works like they have a topic
and they just that's important that's
awesome
they bring on a guest so there's a guy
named uh uh oh crap what's his name uh
air rex
eric's isn't derek but they brought him
on this week i was listening to it
and he was talking about he does similar
things like i
snuck into jake paul's house and took
the couches he was trying to sell
so like another creator's doing a video
trying to
drum up like people participating in it
and then he comes in and like solves the
problem
like that's his that's his he's like
this was just an idea i had
and it you got to be bold right and you
kind of kind of be like i know i'm
nothing but i'm going to solve your
problem and provide way more value for
you than you're providing for me
and that he's like this is my process he
goes and i tried this video
and we did two of the two of those
videos see which one worked and we did
two videos based on that video
so he's like it's the reverse funnel
that's my process i'm just creating tons
and tons and just doing my ideas
yeah and trying not to hemorrhage money
but he's like i'm just
doing tons of videos and then if they
just multiply when they when they hit
and then you just keep
and then you start to narrow your focus
on the things you're good at
and that is what makes youtube
successful he's been doing it for
12 years or something on youtube he's
had like eight channels
and he finally hit on something that's
like he's like i'm gonna get to a
million subs in one year
like he started at zero so started a new
one on january 1st and he now he's
like i don't know i think he's like two
and a half million so he's already beat
it
like easy but he was just talking about
his process and i was like
dude this is so simple you said the word
process in my ears just go whoop
right because athlete that's just i have
to think that way
uh and i was like just just try stuff
do it and then and then have a good have
a good reasoning why you do or do not do
it again
and then ritz repeat do it over and over
again
you know that actually goes really well
with you talked about purpose a lot in
one of your episodes
like everything you do is with purpose
it's with intent
um do you i mean i
i think you probably obviously do is you
take purpose into everything you're
doing so
you're playing games you're enjoying
your life but there's also a purpose
you're like i'm doing this because
this is the platform that i'm building
and then everything you do when it comes
to
your athleticism when with your training
with your mindset it all has
purpose um would you want to expand on
that for me or for any of the listeners
like what
what do you mean by purpose and how does
it help you stay disciplined like how do
you
how do you apply purpose into everything
that you're doing
so purpose is i mean i
i think a lot of people like okay
purpose means having a reason right like
a goal an end goal there's somewhere
you're going and
what you're doing is then move taking
steps towards that place
um and that's kind of the very simple
way to put it
i i kind of phrase it in a way or frame
it
where you are basically
trying to um
oh how do i do this i'm losing my train
of thought
it's funny that you talked about that
earlier like not losing your train of
thought that's what i'm doing right now
um
yeah that's the open format conversation
you're allowed to use your train of
thought
all right i'm gonna answer this one
second i gotta close this
all right so it comes down to being
being mindful of what you're doing um i
think that living in the moment is
uh i don't anyone who's read any sports
psychology book or any sort of like
competitive
psychology book they phrase it different
ways but it's all about um
like whatever you're doing at that
moment
um being aware of what that is and then
how it's how it's gonna
how it's gonna get you to you to your
end goal so i think it starts with that
like that's a skill you have to learn it
uh meditation helps
all kinds of stuff uh to to actively be
engaged in what you're doing
um you know it's like the opposite of
what atd does to you
um and that's what everyone's striving
for i feel like that as a human like
everyone's trying to be like i want to
be
locked into what i'm doing 24 hours a
day seven days a week obviously it's
easier said than done
but um and then you tie that into into
your ability to achieve a purpose or or
have a purpose they kind of they kind of
like
i'm aware of what i'm doing and that and
i'm moving towards this purpose so now
that you've you've made that connection
realizing what that purpose is then puts
you back in the moment so it's like a
snowball effect as
a recycling if you will you keep going
back and forth
um which which allows you to be super
efficient
and and work towards your goal in the
best way possible
and so in baseball terms for example a
huge problem i had was pitching in the
moment
and and people ask me what does that
mean
so what i was doing was when things were
going well
it was because i physically felt well
there were some some other things that
like
for whatever reason i had a lot of sleep
or there was no stress involved it was
like a whatever reason everything was
going my way that day
those are the days where it's easy it
was the days where it was hard
where my valleys were getting really low
those days were bad and my days where i
was good i was
really good so it was just averaging out
us hey it's pretty good
like but in reality like if i could stay
at the higher peaks
longer i would have been insane and so
i'm like that's there
and i see it all the time and people see
it they say they comment on it then when
i'm low they're like what happened
so what's going on and what i realized
was
i'm so i growing up man i was so i'm so
like
i think i i'm an anxious person i get
anxiety um
and it only until recently i've said
that out loud like
i have anxiety this is what this is um
and that was worrying about what just
happened
so either being brain in the past brain
in the future so that we have three
states we're in
right future past and pre present us
um we want to be in present as much as
humanly possible especially when we're
doing something competitive
especially when we're doing something
that like isn't really important to our
lives
um but we spend the majority of our time
in our past thinking about something
that happened to us already or something
that might happen
or planning ahead for the future um in
baseball terms you're literally like
this guy could hit i don't want this guy
to hit a double right now score these
runs so you're thinking about
oh no this is the worst thing that can
happen or you gave up a homer you're
like man
i should have thrown that pitch there
blah blah blah you already gave up the
run so either
you're gonna give up the runs or you
already did give up the runs you don't
want either one of those things to
happen
and that provides a physical response
which
makes it harder and harder and harder
for you to be like dude all i have to do
is throw this one pitch the one place i
want to i have a really good reason to
do it let's just do it
so um that's the thing you learned
the longer you play is like how do i
stay here in the middle and i've been
able to over the last three four years
do that really well and keep me in the
major leagues that has single-handedly
kept me
uh my phys physically mentally uh just
like stuff-wise like how my pitch is
moving stuff
hasn't changed a lot it's just my brain
has been
i've i bought into that i got there kind
of a little bit by taking
bits and pieces out of books i read and
people i talked to kind of developed my
own kind of way to think about it in a
very like
structured mathematical way um
i actually call it afe i talked about in
this in one of my episodes but like
analyze focus then execute execution is
physical and
analyzing is mental and focus is mental
two of the three steps are mental
they're throwing a pitch right though uh
the physical stuff you can't
you really there's very little you can
do to change it in the in
in real time anyway so your mental side
is the is the best part and they happen
in that order every time
so if you skip one or you mess one up
it's probably gonna affect the next step
yep and so the more often you do that
you break down your pitches and then
when something bad does happen you can
then look at three steps and be like
which one was it
and most of the time it's either
execution or your plan
if it's it can't be if it's you have
full control of your focus the other two
you don't
yeah right for in terms of getting
results so
i was like oh i just have to be obsessed
with this focus part which is
having a purpose was allowed me to focus
the best coming to the point where i was
like
i have a reason why i need to focus
because it is the most important thing i
need to do
that's my purpose i'm like this will get
me to my results better than anything
else
once i made that connection working on
my focus
day in and day out became much easier
and then i you just saw my results just
turn up right and so then i applied that
to video games and to and i'm still
doing it and it's very hard
um i'm still kind of i'm not quite there
uh frankly
um where i'll be i'll be streaming or
something i'll be like i've just kind of
been going through the motions for like
four hours
i'm just kind of playing not really
talking to chad that's huge for me
because people want to ask me baseball
questions and me being engaged is like
the most important thing because i'm
just not
i'm not a world-class gamer i'm a good
game i play games well
but i'm not like no one's like dude this
guy's nuts like that's not
my brand my brand is super hyper engaged
hyper like
having conversations like we are now um
and so
i'm constantly like okay how can i use
focus to then
play the game at a good level but like
the content is tailored to me talking to
them and playing and like creating that
connection
i'm still finding it uh and they get
changes game to game too that's kind of
a hard thing
um but i have realized that the chat
over here on this side monitor
these people talking that's my purpose
for doing this
and this recently i've attached that to
purpose and so
um once you attach a purpose to whatever
the thing you're doing
then you can lock in what you're
focusing focused on
yeah if that makes sense so purpose and
focus are like hey
you know bedfellows hand in hand and
they always are and so
if you find yourself you're like what
what am i doing if you're ever like
what am i doing if you ask that self
you're not focused on something
and you might not have a purpose or
you're not focused on the thing that's
going to get you the purpose you're like
i want to get there i know that
so what am i doing right now and why if
you just ask yourself that question
sounds really simple
answer and then answer it honestly
because sometimes you'll be like
i don't think i like this as much as i
actually do maybe you just need to not
be doing it
yeah sometimes that's the answer um and
it becomes
much clearer and much easier to uh to
kind of buy
in to to your purpose once you're honest
with yourself about whether or not it's
what you want it to be right
and like you were talking about before
that just kind of provides you to be
happy uh
it gets you to a place you want to be
and whether that's building a huge
following on youtube
or or finding your process for whatever
it is um
this is it's all interconnected it's all
just like you you create that
that purpose you lock in that focus and
then you develop the process
how that gets you to that purpose like
that's kind of a those are the words
those are like the buzz words for me
yeah no i mean it's brilliant though it
works perfectly do you ever
uh have you know guys like tony robbins
they talk about a state change
where it's like tony robbins is where
right before he walks on stage he has
like this mini trampoline
and then he has this like does this
little spin thing
and he says some words in his head some
mantras whatever and then he walks on
stage and he's
on like he's just in there do you have
in to me that
that seems like it's almost like you
know what your purpose is but you're
turning on your purpose like i'm
i'm installing i'm hitting i'm hitting
restart on my operating system
so i'm starting from my purpose do you
have anything like that like when you
walk on the mound or when you even
go to your gaming room you're like it's
time to work it's time to pursue my
purpose
that's super interesting that yeah i
said i love that i've actually read a
couple
tony robbins books he is he is that's i
think that's that's one thing that like
maybe your
your layman kind of gets a little bit
like whoa because it's a little like
it's extreme
he he does extreme stuff like he takes
really cold showers right in the morning
to wake himself up for a minute
um and state changes are his purp your
purpose changes depending on what
what you're doing like when he's
backstage his purpose changes
when he's on stage and he knows that and
he knows when his his
his uh uh his stages what he says is a
state change his states have different
purposes
so sometimes he is relaxed relax and
stay relaxation sorry state
um and he's chilling and he does have
those a lot of people probably think
he's high energy all the time no i
guarantee you that dude crashes harder
than anybody probably
dude no doubt and uh uh so
do i have something similar i'm trying
to
so it's crazy you asked that because
recently
this last covet season like messed me up
in a different like
like was a different challenge for me um
there was a
i'm going into free agency year there's
three there's two months there's this
existential threat
of covet us getting it but also even
more importantly just i felt
i felt irresponsible being on the field
i i'm like dude we shouldn't
be showing people that we should all be
out like doing whatever we want right
now we shouldn't be
like we're not sending the right message
because i believe that we just didn't do
a good job handling this thing which is
very clear
i don't care who you are it's just clear
it's just it hasn't been done well
um and we're still not doing well which
is unfortunate but
so i was dealing with a lot of that and
then i was like okay and then after this
year is my free agency here i don't know
i gotta get a team i gotta pitch well i
gotta do
stuff so like i had a item i had an
anxiety attack in the middle of the
season
right after coming off a bad outing i
walked off the field went inside to get
mad i got mad at this huge emotional
outbreak of me and then i kind of went
to a knee and i could not stand up and i
was like what the hell is going on
and it was like shortness of breath i
didn't feel weak or anything i just like
my body was like
no i'm not getting up i'm like yes you
are and it was weird
and it was i was embarrassed by my my
i was like you know you don't want to do
that in public nobody does but like i
wasn't on the field but
my trainer ran up he's like hey and then
our head doctor was like i think you had
a panic attack an anxiety attack and you
have generally really bad anxiety i'm
like it's never been this bad
um but i've realized i've had stuff like
that in the past and
and i was like i need to
i need to have something where i can
that's a state i went into when i didn't
want to
right and so when you talk about state
changes i was like maybe being aware
when those states change is
better um and maybe from from good
locked in too bad is more something that
i need to be
aware of and so i've actually been
working on
mastering breathing trying a bunch of
breathing techniques i did uh
tons of uh tons and tons of meditation
for a long time before i was diagnosed
with adult add
or adhd and it got like some super like
light
um non-stimulant medication so like i
real once i started taking i was like oh
that cloud wasn't me being tired it was
like actually like
having trouble focusing long periods of
time everyone's on the spectrum i'm just
a little bit on it it helps
um and i haven't had to meditate as much
but um
so the breathing is my physical response
i'm a very very
like tight person kind of like all my
muscles are tight all the time it's just
how i made so like i tend to go there a
lot
when i do that you can't breathe and
that's why my your
anxiety just you know goes way up
because you're having the
your physical responses first and then
your brain panics because your body's
physically
reacting to something and so you're like
physically constricting your mental yeah
yeah exactly you're physically
constricting there's no blood flow and
you're not breathing until your brain
can't relax
uh and so um i've that's
that's a state change that i'm working
on going like literally getting myself
to where i'm so full of air that i can't
breathe
anymore and then letting it all out one
time dude it's it's a thousand percent
i change states i'm like okay it's gonna
be cool i can start solving the problem
that i that
caused it in the first place so that
that's an example of that
um when i'm out in the while i'm out in
the field though and when i'm going from
i'm just a spectator to i'm about to be
in the game in five minutes
there is a switch that flips but there's
a there's a there's a build
up so we all say we kind of know what
situation could be us
like we're up by two runs starting
pitchers pitching in the sixth inning
and he gives up a guy on second there's
nobody on
no but no ounce i'm like this could be
me i might have to come in and get him
out of this inning this is my job
so when that happens you start to go
everyone shows their anxiety like you
get like anxious kind of
intis you starting to anticipate it that
changes i get up and start walking
around
they're like you know like moving like
trying not to
forget any of the i start going over in
my head how i'm going to pitch to
whoever's coming up and we had a guy
sergio romo three-time world series
winner
closer who uh he's super like
like loves to talk loves to be sociable
talks the whole time
two innings before he's gonna go in he's
like crouched down he's like picking his
nails and like try always trimming his
nails making sure they're all perfect
like that's that's his nervous like
anxious thing
yeah we have that yeah we got tyler
duffy he can't sit down the hole in it
at the whole game
but he doesn't get nervous before he
just like he's one of those guys like i
need
i'm not gonna start doing anything until
the phone rings and then he just takes
off shirt starts throwing
it's time to go that's the way he deals
with it i build up sergio really builds
up
so like we all hear different things
once you get the ball you start throwing
it
that's like now you're in such you've
done so many times that you get like it
goes from
comfort yeah and and it's like
you've created this comfortable place
that isn't comfortable for anybody but
you
and that's kind of how we change our
states when we start to throw we get
anticipatory and then
once they grab the ball you create it's
like a closing of a loop
you your brain goes end of that stage
now we're into a new one
and and that that is what it suffices as
i
i love uh one last thing i want to say
about this
is i was actually listening to a podcast
by brene brown who and she did
uh one about closing stress cycles so
about stress cycles and there's a books
uh today had the authors of the books on
two twin sisters
talking about how we all go through
stress like stress isn't avoidable like
you just get like you go to work you're
like oh god oh god oh god
and the the thing is it's a it's
emotional it's emotional it's physical
it's everything combined
and you have to close the loop if you
never close the loop if you go to bed
and you're still in the loop
you won't sleep well the next day you'll
be more stressed and it just makes it
worse and worse and worse
that's when people burn out when you
never close the loop
so you do something physical at the end
of every day to signify i am done
with the stressor like i'm done with
work i'm done with
i don't need to do anything more tonight
and this is what i do to make it feel so
like
my wife and i we didn't realize that's
what this was for us but the moment
we're both on the couch at the same time
we're both sitting on the couch we're
done
we're both done and we look over and the
cat we have
we have our animals with us and we're
like we don't have to do anything we
just got to watch tv that's it yes
we can do whatever we want now and that
close like your body just goes okay
there's nothing i can do
i'm not gonna do anything you could tell
me to do something i'm not gonna do it
so i don't need to be stressed um and
they were just talking about go for a
brisk walk so like you know that once
you're on that walk
your day is your your stress day is done
and your
you day is begun and it's not about
self-care
like everyone with self-care blah blah
it's just about thinking it
like a math problem you just need to fit
like solve the equation finish the
equation
you sometimes you finish the equation by
just finding something
that signifies to your brain into your
body that it's over
yes just for the day and then in the
morning you get up and you're kind of
energized ready to take it on again
yeah um and whether that's like you
accomplished a lot that day whatever it
is for you
just finding that end so like like you
said you're changing your state
again like that's exactly what tony's
talking about yeah
dude i like how i i say you give things
power
and i think that that's that's a huge
thing so you can actually say i mean
instead definitely being a creator and
definitely being
you know someone who you know you're
know you're known to
you know you're not drake walking around
but you're known to the public in a lot
of ways
and so being able to kind of like turn
off the
the being on like i'm on my point i'm
living through my purpose i'm doing the
things
that trevor may does to get his work
done and when you sit on the couch you
look over at kate
okay we're done with it you you bring it
to your conscious awareness and you say
this the switch is off you know and
that's
that's super powerful you know we give
things power and i think
a lot of us um this would be a good
leeway into
awareness itself you know that's
something that for me
you know i've heard the word before i
knew about it i knew it was like
but until you really start digging into
like what is awareness
and what does it mean to be self-aware
and how do i
you know when we walk out to our car and
we go get in our car we don't realize
that
we we open the door handle and we turn
to get out of our house and then
you lock the door and then you walk over
and you physically grab
your door handle and you touch it and
whatever like we don't notice all those
things that we do
in between we're just going we're just
you have our momentum
but bringing awareness to what we're
doing then we can kind of insert our
meaning into it
and just kind of stop the the ever
changing the ever
just avalanching situation that is our
thoughts
um so what trevor when it when it came
to your life
was there ever a moment where you kind
of realized oh
i'm discovering self-awareness
like this i i'm intentionally becoming
aware and i wasn't before
um even we could even transition into
you talked a lot about your frustration
like you had trouble dealing with
emotions when you were younger
which i think a lot of us dealt with um
still deal with you know a lot of us
deal with
battling our emotions but bringing
awareness
to the conscious thought or what's
actually going on you can start to
handle these things and
really give them power in the positive
way yeah so i would say
the biggest i think the biggest year
that i started to realize that
is um in 2012
i was in double a and that's when i
talked about like i realized
how little in little awareness i had
when i was on the mound i had lots of
awareness after
i was like oh i could have done this
this and this this this
i was like but one thing lacking here is
my self-awareness right
and i started to get into i started to
get into um
it's okay i started to get into uh
meditation um and a an app called i'm a
huge i was like apps are great
at that time an app called headspace a
lot of people might do it's got a month
a yearly subscription
made by a guy named andy pootie comb
putty comb
um an english guy uh and he's his voice
is so good dude
it's so good he's great and now he's got
i think he's got a he's got a woman that
does it with him too now
um but he's he's phenomenal uh
and the app's great and there's tons and
tons and tons and tons and tons of
the content on there now is incredible
like it's way worth
worth the money times three um
but that's when i became one something
he used to say to me that really locked
me in was
we the practice was all based around
like he was giving you
things to focus on but like and i would
lose it constantly
obviously at the beginning and but when
he lost he goes all right if you lost it
just forgive yourself and then go back
and you're like holy
hell this is so like forgiving yourself
for like oh dang it
lost it again well i'm back now like if
you had that that way
like instead of getting frustrated about
it he just said you forgave yourself and
i it was something for whatever reason
really easy for me to do
and so i started applying that
immediately
um and then i started applying it just
in real life like you said
walking out of the car i'm like alright
i'm opening the car or i'm opening the
garage
all right i'm driving out and then i
would like see how long it could stay
there before i was like go back on
autopilot because we're we're we're so
sun conscious beings like you just can't
be conscious all the time it's like it's
exhausting right yeah which is a whole
nother thing
um but i i think it it
that's kind of when i started to realize
that self-awareness was
lacking like i just wasn't self-aware i
just i wasn't and i
we have a term for it in baseball um
called feel okay so like you
you're you're aware of like the people
around you and what you're saying
and every once in a while you run into a
teammate that like just doesn't get
that like he for example like complain
about when he's being pitched and when
like
like problems that literally every other
guy has like everyone's has the same
problems
and he's complaining to you and he
doesn't realize that like he's preaching
the choir do you know what i mean you're
listening dude
yeah we we're we literally do we all did
this
like what do you mean like he's a rookie
that's like i never get a pitch like
dude you're rookie
like you know they don't trust you yet
and that's very very obvious and i don't
understand why you don't know that but
it's like a lacking feel
uh guys who why you used to have a
teammate who just burst into song all
the time just like
start singing he's awful like he played
guitar
and just wrote these horrible songs and
he's just a terrible singer
but he just insisted he loved it and he
was a nice guy
and we kind of deal with it but we're
like dude
stop like look around though yeah just
like
read the room to read the room like
that's the big thing so like
uh uh sometimes you gotta read your own
room
you gotta be like why am i doing the
thing i'm doing
yeah is this helpful exactly is this
helpful
and a lot of times it isn't um
uh i want to attach this to it a little
bit too
we talked about the just the last thing
about ending the stress cycle and kind
of
uh being aware like this is your brain
is just like
shutting off i like to think of that as
kind of a switch flipping to the other
side so your purpose changes
so it's not like you're going from on to
off it's going from purpose to purpose
i think that's something because people
think off they think like
i don't have to think anymore that's not
that's not what it is what it is is
um your purpose is now rest you're like
i need to rest so that later
the other purpose benefits from that yes
so like that's hard for me
but until you're aware of that until you
have the self-awareness to know that
like
stress drains me the other side
recharges me that's your that's your
cycle life cycle
um once you if you don't have the
awareness to know like how much
something drains you and how much
something
something recharges you then you can't
find that quote-unquote balance that
everyone talks about
um and so self-awareness buys right into
that self-awareness is like the most
valuable thing
any person in the world can learn
you know i i i i don't like to talk
uh about you know politics very much
um i don't think it's gonna be a
politics thing but like
the guy at the top had very little
self-awareness for a very long time he
had none
and he had has none he doesn't and it's
a little bit of indifference
like it's not valuable for him to worry
about the things that he says or does
because there are no consequences right
and so that signaled to a lot of people
that having self-awareness isn't
important dude and that's
100 and that that is what i hated like
that is my that is my like that's
heartbreaking to me yeah
that besides like oh her tax is going to
go up or down like who gives a [__]
what are you making okay yeah what are
you making it's okay to just
not think about your actions or think
about the fact that you're a leader
that you're yeah all these things and
all that stuff's important and we all
know that
everyone knows that like to some level
right
everyone knows that leadership is
important everyone knows that like
self-awareness and being like and being
considerate of other people is a
positive trait
everyone knows that even the people that
like ardently follow him know that will
say oh yeah obviously being considered
people
is is important then why do you
put not doing that on such a high
pedestal for other things right
there's something else um but just in
terms of talking about being aware
and it's so important and if every
single person like really really
really put in the time and effort to
learn it develop it
and really really see the value and
being aware of your surroundings being
aware of yourself and being aware of
what you want and where you're going
the world just be like continue to
become a better place not that it's
i genuinely think it is a good place and
i'm glad i'm i'm glad i'm in the world
yeah um but uh and this is just
we're always just if you just know that
you're always
under construction you you are always a
work in progress
um and you're aware of that and and
you're always aware of the things and
the decisions you're making you're just
always going to get better
yeah never stops 100
yeah i like to it's a like you hear the
term woke
and i like to just combat it all with
saying like you're never
awake you're never woke you're always
awakening like
when you're when you're on a path of
just trying to be good or trying to like
live whatever fulfillment is to you
personally
you're always awakening like every day
you're learning something new and every
day you're
you're going towards that thing and dude
self-awareness i read this book
um by anthony demaio um i think it's
called self-awareness or just awareness
but oh my gosh like it's it's this uh
uh it's it's it's kind of a lecture
format i listen to it on
um audible and it's just kind of
restating these things that are
so on the surface you know like because
it's like what we're talking about you
know
like there's buzzfeed words and it's
stuff you hear in meditation a lot of
times that stuff is
you're like well duh you know okay but
then you realize how often you're not
thinking that way how often you're not
in awareness for me i
um i don't know i
i feel like i became such a better
person when i intentionally discovered
self-awareness when i started really
trying to understand why it is that i'm
doing what i'm doing
you know it's like this huge change in
my life like it's like where i feel like
i really started growing up
was inserting self-awareness and um
realizing how often i was
self-conscious or thinking about what
other people are thinking about me
instead of just
being with what i'm doing and
intentionally doing it um
so trevor you used to have um you talked
about before just
when you were younger i mean you've been
playing baseball since you were i think
six years old you said
um and so you've dealt with a lot of
emotions and a lot of pressure that you
put on yourself you're very competitive
um
so you used to like you you would get
angry and
and frustrated on the mound what do you
think was one of the biggest factors
how you started coping with it and how
you started dealing with it you know i
mean if you were giving advice to
the younger you or or younger kids
coming up who
um you know maybe they maybe they rage
when they when they throw or they get
back to the
to the um to the dugout and they they
throw their glove and they're ticked off
you know me i was a skateboarder
i've plenty of times i've i've stomped
on my board or i had friends who just
you know you wreck and you can't seem to
hit the trick whatever it is
and you're just over it and you rage
whatever
but that's not beneficial to us you know
letting our emotions just fly like that
so
let's talk a little bit about you know
you overcoming your frustration issues
from
when you were younger yeah so uh
i think that that like you said
intentionally discovering
self-awareness and then creating
strategies to improve um
was the first like wow this is directly
correlated with frustration like i can
more accurately determine when i'm going
to be
frustrated and then the variables that
are in play when i
am um and so it came down to a few
things
uh like i said i i was on the add
spectrum a little bit more than i
thought i was like i didn't take
medication but
uh i kind of like in my early 20s and
what i dabbled in all kinds of different
like you know dried out or all tried eye
bands tried like concert i tried all of
the brands and all the dosages and stuff
because
uh you know for studying or what
whatever it was because even though i
didn't go to college i was like always
had a project going where i would love
to just like focus for eight hours a lot
of times it was producing music
and uh which was which was great and and
i realized that there were some things
that like
you know gave me the oh wired feeling
that a lot of people get when they're
not supposed to be one at
all taken at all um and there were days
where i was like this feels like
just i feel pretty even yes that's not
how i'm supposed to feel with this i
might need to take this
and so when i went and got checked out
they were like
yeah you're probably you probably could
use the low dose like ritalin or
something or um and then that
that got me interval irritable so i was
like no no no i'll never forget she
asked me she goes
so what have you tried him like no no no
nothing nothing okay so what have you
tried like she was 100 people
tell the police she was 100 like
everyone who comes in here has tried it
before and they know what works and what
doesn't
already because that's why they're here
they've figured it out
i was like okay so i've tried bypants
and adderall and i tried named like nine
different ones
like geez uh uh yeah so just try this uh
stratera and it's just non-stimulant you
don't need
so basically you need a t-ue therapeutic
use when you're an adult like if you're
close to 30 man getting a t.u.e in the
mlb is like
if you didn't come up through the minors
with one like you're just getting a new
like getting
prescribed to a medication that is a
stimulant that is actually cheating for
other people
like is really hard to get so um but the
non-stimulant one just like the you have
to
take a higher dose and take it more
often and it doesn't affect you the same
way
uh very low addiction rates and stuff
uh was it good and i i take that now and
it's great so that was one big thing
like realizing that that happened
something there was that was a little
bit more out of my control uh the way
that you do it too a lot of times is
just drinking lots of caffeine
i drink so if you remember me at all i
was smashing energy drinks my whole
life dude me too i'm with you yeah yeah
so so um that helped
um and it helped just like in the
morning be like okay boom
this is my that's my my uh the way i i
function and this is helping
so that helped a lot where um i didn't
feel like
things like sped up on me too fast and i
was able to stay self-aware a little
longer like i knew what the external
factors are affecting me um now
in terms of practice um i started to
to to practice the i want to focus on
this thing for this long
when i lost it forgiving myself and
moving on the forgiveness part
remove the everything's your fault right
from my head
that was that was a big thing and when i
was young that was a huge huge problem
it was like
i was so worried about what people
thought
and then getting the results that then
would they get the
adoration or the or the acceptance
that um if
getting the result and then the
adoration both didn't happen
together that was the only way i wasn't
frustrated so i was starting to be
frustrated 80
of the time in some ways just like on a
spectrum and that's so unhealthy
and then i then i realized that neither
one of those things are remotely close
to being process oriented
and in order to continue to get better
at baseball i would have to become
process oranges so like oh
16 17 18 i started to really get into
the whole
process mindset i read a book called
mind gym that my sister gave me who was
a college
softball player for four years she was
like hey this should help you a lot
you're frustrated a lot she was too she
was the same way
probably not as much as me but like
similar
uh that we i think we get it from our
dad i i'm frankly uh
thanks dad but thanks dad um because he
was uh he was a big
competitive guy and he gets frustrated
uh but so
she gave me that book it's kind of stuff
about alex rodriguez and
a lot of stuff just about like being in
the moment
so i was like process process is my
thing
i think that i have big goals i think
that thinking long term is more
important than short term
when that all happened i'm like all
right let's lock into the process
and let's start creating um positive
uh results in the process not the actual
at the end
the results aren't at the end they're in
the process now so you start checking
i'm a very like i realized about myself
late a little bit later probably mid-20s
that like
i'm a huge to-do list like check check
things off guy and that's like
that is how i close my stress cycle
so stress and frustration were connected
directly
so i started to say okay how can i start
to do that in real time
like on the mount or real time in some
sort of competitive way
to where everything that i practice is
then being implemented one step at a
time
in the moment so i'm like okay i need to
go over here and i need to do this or i
need to throw this pitch like this
because i know this about that guy
when it became that then i was like oh
okay i
i i found what i needed to do check
did i do it check yeah did did what i
want to happen happen yes
check next pitch and then you have to do
it over and over again now that list of
check boxes is
huge for a game especially as a starter
so it took a lot of practice and it
takes a lot of effort
but if you're a young person going into
anything
where where there's going to be like a
point of time where you need to be
locked in
whether that's work or whether that's
like an uh or
a sport or whether that's like you're a
dj you got to be like locked in and
crushing your stuff
and being like what song's playing
what's coming up next how am i going to
transition these things what do i need
to prepare and there's not you're never
stopped
um when you're djing even uh and and
that allows you to if you're in the
moment the whole time during a dj set
you
you just love it so much more yeah it
was so much more fun because you've
noticed people
enjoying it you notice yourself enjoying
you notice your anticipation for the
next song
all that stuff right it applies to every
single thing you can do
in a day um and it just makes everything
enjoyable so
i would say create find out what your
process is the uh your purpose for where
you're trying to go long term
and then your process for getting there
and then if you start checking those
boxes and every box you check
inside the process is you achieving
you're accomplishing you're getting it
done
doing your work as you put it in uh uh
over time over years months day like
however long it is
you're gonna you're gonna you're gonna
you're gonna look back and not recognize
that person
and you might not even notice it which
is hilarious to say because you're
been you've been so in the moment for so
long
that like now you can't like zone out
for long term and see the differences
yeah which is it's really funny to think
about it's like a weird uh
it's ironic retrospect is a real weird
thing
it is weird but uh that that's i
thinking about it that way i just i
switched what i saw as a
as results um as success you change in
your brain what success means
uh and and you're moving like other
people
like worrying about because the the
results are always like connected to
okay put in baseball terms results are
always connected to a writer writing
about you
fans talking about you your teammates
talking about you
your coach putting you in situations
those are all
all reinforcement of a positive result
of a game
right that's all other people mm-hmm
and i understand in order to stay as a
baseball player you have to have good
results
so if you think about it it's really
hard to not focus on results when that
literally dictates whether or not you
get a job
it does but if your process is good
those results end up being there anyways
right so you ha and that's trust that's
just trust from its most
basic form it's your you're just you're
like i know this is
this is the way and if i do this i'm
that definition is going to be there
um one way shape or form and it's going
to be okay and i
forgive myself if i mess up along the
way and that's
that's it like and over and over and
over again that is it it's that simple
uh and if you think if you think of it
that way and you you find the way to
phrase it yourself to where you can go
back there faster and faster and faster
because like me i was a big math guy
like i said an equation i thought about
it as an equation
box checked very like step by step by
step by step i'm a recipe guy that's how
i
how i feel like i'm comfortable learning
and remembering and making sure that i
can bring myself back there
and some people are like it's a picture
that they remember or like a moment in
their life
that they go back to where they made it
where they made a connection their brain
and they're like
every time they go back there they make
the connection again a lot of people do
it like that
um whatever it is you gotta just find
that way find those those keys and those
those
um those uh way to make you fire and
know that that's your process and just
tell
how when you wake up in the morning it's
the first thing you do and yeah here we
are 31 i'm still doing it always going
to be doing it
uh what i'm trying to accomplish in my
life what my purpose is it's going to
fluctuate
all the time but i know that i can form
i can put together a process follow it
well and get to where i
want to go yeah yeah dude i i think like
uh
you you seem to be very growth mindset
you know versus growth versus fixed
mindset um just
kind of always improving and leaning
towards um
towards your purpose uh did you
i mean we come from the same town you
know so we
and this is not a bash on our town
there's a lot of wonderful people here
and there's a lot of awesome stuff like
there's a lot of cool
this whole area is really great in so
many ways but um
to me sometimes i think that i see a lot
of fixed mindsets in people who
don't um they don't really understand
that you can change
who you are like you can change yourself
into like you're not just born
this exact person and you're living out
this storyline you know you can say
these things are frustrating me or like
something i enjoy you know say
playing baseball is kind of getting uh
muddied by me getting frustrated so i
can change it instead of saying
well i just get frustrated and that's
just what i do that's how i was born
you know there's a lot of value in
turning on
the the growth mindset do you think that
you've always had
a growth mindset like even from when you
were younger
i think that i think that my that's one
thing my parents did really well my dad
again like i said i got frustration from
him
but getting better at things or like
having
a really like he's just a
hard-working-ass guy
like he just worked really really hard
like it's crazy to think about hard he
worked
um and i didn't see it a lot like i only
went to his work like three times in my
life
like he worked at calama chemical and he
was uh you know like a like a shift
supervisor and like a like a
like a floor manager like for the
machines and like so he would make sure
things were going he said he would nap
every night like he works wing shift so
like you just leave at 6 00 pm come back
at 6 a.m
and just be exhausted and sleep and just
make money and
let us live our life basically and then
he'd get four days off and then
he go he tried to plan that around like
basketball tournament stuff he's our
basketball coach and he was an
amazing amazing father but he just like
that subconsciously planted like
this is normal working your ass off is
normal
and and so that was a big thing for me
um
just like you can just work really
really you got to work really really
hard
to do anything and then he would always
he always this is a really cool story
that i actually have not told very much
and i always remember it i've told my
wife
probably and some close friends but uh
he used to do something when i was young
like probably
between when i was like
five to eight he would tell me things
called trevor stories
so like could go to bed he would go lay
down next to me
you know and like tell me a story where
i was the main character
and i was doing something crazy like and
chibi something amazing
and i think that that went like so far
and it's crazy to think like how much
that affected me because that is
literally like my ethos
so he's like he's like trevor may comes
up to bat with you know two outs in the
world series
hits the grand slam to win it or like
it's the game winning shot or hits a
game winning free throw like that was
his big thing too so he'd always like
frame like
high pressure free throw not like a
hitting a three
because he's like i'm gonna put you in a
situation where it's more likely this
happens to you you know what i mean
uh and so uh or like football he's like
uh uh
you know makes the game when he passes i
want to be a quarterback and uh he would
always ask me what my favorite sport is
and uh
like depending on what the season was it
would change from basketball to baseball
like
until i was i realized that i wasn't
gonna get taller than six five and six
five just simply isn't tall enough to
play basketball in the nba for
a white dude who doesn't move really
really really well um
no offense to white guys but come on bro
uh
and so um baseball became the the wave
uh and i was like until then though i
would just switch
because i knew he loved basketball and
he wanted me to play basketball and
um and then he'd be okay well we gotta
go do x y and z we gotta go shoot this
many free throws we're gonna go do this
or you gotta go do this and
you know that's just what it takes he
was just always like that's what it
takes
and so i was like cool so i always had
big dreams when i was little
um and that where i was and my
environment had nothing to do with that
like that was something that just like
permeated pat he just wanted me to think
that way and if it didn't happen it
didn't happen but it was just like
i think it just was like a fun thing to
do and then he realized that like what
the value it had long term and now he
still does it he still texts me like
hey man you know uh after good outing
he's like absolutely incredible
you're this pitch this [__] this [__]
are incredible you're better than this
guy
he like things like that like he has no
no no chill when it comes to that
and he goes and you can be an all-star
blah blah blah he still doesn't i'm 31
years old
yeah it is awesome and it just it's
random um and so that was huge
uh and i think that growth mindset is so
so important because once you create
like again the purpose like that
long-term purpose like
20 years in the future purpose like i
want to play in the major leagues and i
want to do this
once you create that then creating the
path for how to do it is like
now you're once you accept that's where
you want to go
next thing to do is just do the do the
path
yeah and the thing i think that is
lacking sometimes especially in smaller
towns and
and what have you is people might not
just might not think big enough right
away when they're young like
you know what i mean like maybe they
don't create that purpose far enough
to where far enough away like it doesn't
seem possible so you set limits early
um and that's just sometimes that's the
way it is and and
and um but i think that fixed mindsets
come from
a little bit of uh sometimes
hopelessness sometimes things that feel
like like
lack of control that's a big thing
that's a big
that's a huge like issue that's a huge
topic of discussion
um but uh at the end of the day man like
you can change it whenever you want you
see people doing this left right and
center all the time people who were 40
were fixed mindset for 30 years lived in
a small town and then
when they're 40 to 50 son like started a
business and then became a millionaire
like
in 40 students exactly and that exists
people do that all the time people are
doing it currently right now
all over the place um and it comes down
and sometimes it comes down to to life
experience like
what have you seen possible like what
have what have you seen in person like
where have you gone and who have you
experienced who you've been around who
stories have you heard
that's important the quest for knowledge
is really important too um
but uh uh you know it's it's just all
about
uh um you know buying in and
and buying into what you can do and and
what's important to you
but um you know i i think that something
was important for me too and this is
once i found that that major purpose
that big one
i got to places where my back felt like
i felt like i was cornered
like my back was against the wall and i
was being like i have to make this
change or i'm gonna fail
and there's nothing there's no bigger
motivator than that
um at all uh
to where your purpose is so much more
important to you than failing
like you're not that it's just not an
option i've had
several several things in my life where
i can fail there's just not like
i couldn't my brain wouldn't my brain
couldn't actually like
create a scenario in its head like i
couldn't think about i
didn't even know what it looked like yes
and that
now that i'm thinking about is super
valuable now i'm a reliever so
i switch from being a starter to a
reliever uh in 2016.
um and then i got twenty tommy john 2017
they wanted me come back as a starter
again
and i saw a bunch of young guys on my
aaa team with me when i was rehabbing
that were all
available to be called up anytime they
were young they were exciting people
wanted them up big leagues i was like
you know what
i'm competing against a bunch of young
guys again i might not be given the
opportunity
and i want to be a reliever again so put
me in the bullpen so they put me in the
bullpen
start throwing harder and now i am what
i am and i'm free agent right now
like with really good prospects of
getting a nice a nice contract that i've
never even
had before like this could be my come up
here and
i realize that i strive in those back to
the wall
situations and as a reliever your back
is just against the wall when you go in
like every day like there is like a you
can't mess up because it's your fault if
you mess up like at all there's no
the wiggle room for for mistakes it's
just like very little especially the
later you go in the game when you're
closing or whatever that's why closing
is what it's called like
what it is like why they they get paid
the most of all relievers
it's because you're the your ability to
make a mistake and then have your team
pick you up later it's diminished
because it's the last inning
so if you give up the lead then you lose
there's no time to come back
so it's that harder to get those outer
harder to get
over time and but your back is literally
immediately back against the wall and
then you have to pitch well and you got
to find a way to get it done and that
there's there is no one coming to help
you
it's you you're there by yourself and
your job
and when i get in that mode i i get
better
and and that i realized that i was like
that's a reliever man that's a high
leverage guy that is like
give me the ball when the game's online
and i will take care of it
um and it's a little bit thankless at
times like sometimes like no one wants
to even acknowledge you unless you blow
it
um and that's just the nature of the
game but that's like my wheelhouse man
and i love it
and so like when i explain why i love
relieving i'm like
i just like yes i'm gonna make less
money in my career yes
that's just again i forgive i forgive
myself for making that decision
like move on it's just reality and uh
it's not like it's not good money it's
just not as much as a starter would get
um and but
i'm also a much better pitcher because
i'm in this role so like it's
i wouldn't have the opportunity i'm
having now either so it's just like two
sides of a coin
but you know if you get yourself in
situations where
you want to accomplish something so bad
and you're like i have
like for example if that meant like i
have to leave this place
right if that was the thing if like my
environment is causing me to feel this
way and i don't want to feel this way
anymore
my goal is to be happy and do this other
thing and pursue this other thing that i
want to do and i have to be somewhere
else to do it
your backs against the wall how you
react at that point is a growth might
like you better
either fix and you're like oh well i'm
going to fail or your growth you're like
nah
yeah i'm going to find a way and yeah
that's the difference um
but anything great anything anything
great that's worth
like that you that you want that's going
to make you happy it's worth fighting
for
so i would say uh but it's all about
that it's all about that grand purpose
that big
big beautiful juicy goal at the end um
and i was fortunate enough that as an
athlete
i just got i and i got really lucky my
dad put those big things in my mind and
then my
my body grew into a person physically
they could actually do it
yeah right so yeah
there's there's some luck there yeah no
that that's huge i i feel like a lot of
uh like what you were saying with
meditation where
um when you realize you were thinking
and it's just like oh just forgive
yourself and return back to the task at
hand
i feel like that plays so much into just
everything you're doing like
it all just intertwines with living your
purpose and
and handling like your backs against the
wall
and it's you know it's a do or die it's
like i'm here
and i'm gonna handle it and i'm i'm
gonna push away all these other things
that are going to try to bring me down
um yeah thanks for sharing those stories
too i mean that's that's super great and
that
sounds like your your dad instilled
stilled within you some good
like visualization techniques even you
know i mean imagine imagine
young trevor just laying in bed like you
probably saw yourself on the mound you
know you probably saw yourself
you know you because i use visualization
a lot too
before i even got into meditation with
my djing
i would uh i did a lot when i would do
cardio like that would keep me
distracted during car like okay i'm
gonna run for an hour
i'm gonna listen to like one of my old
dj mixes or something
and just visualize myself in front of a
crowd and like once
yeah i do that too man yeah i still get
that
i still get that i'll find a song back
man this would be so fun to play in
front of people yes
yes it's underrated like just just that
visualization technique you know
they say that our uh like our brains
don't really fully understand like you
can get the feeling
like you get chills you get shivers and
you just really think about it in your
brain like
your body chemistry thinks that you're
actually there just like the virtual
reality thing
it's very uh it's a powerful technique
you know visualization is cool you've
been doing it since you were
at such a young age i want to talk about
uh
just just real quickly i want to just
ask your
your meditation practice so is that
pretty much the gist of your meditation
practice like do you
do you have a daily or do you just kind
of do it when you know it's time to get
to work it's time to get get super
focused or you know you've been slipping
off
and you just pull up headspace and
follow through that's your main
yeah kind of um and it used to be daily
i did i actually uh completed the 365
day challenge once
um did it for every day for a year um
and actually
since i've been prescribed to terra it
hasn't been as i've been i finding it a
little bit more natural to kind of like
you know snap in um i've actually
in my workouts this off season i'm
focusing a lot more on yoga so you know
it's built
you know built together um just uh so
i'm i'm kind of double dipping a little
bit there and just making sure i'm
focused on the practice
um and like really getting the most out
of every position and what kind of stuff
which kind of keeps you in the moment
the whole time um but there's days where
i'm like dude i've i'm all over the
place like
if i say i feel like super
keyed up and i don't know why because i
mean
i still get there although i still that
still happens to me all the time it
happens to everybody
um then i'll just go to i'm like andy
come just talk to me for five minutes
and then they'll calm me down enough to
realize what was going on
and to you know and to let it go or or
or actually get myself a new state where
it's up i can tackle the problem more
effectively um and that that it's become
a strategy
more so than like something that i feel
because like i said i'm a box checker so
when i start to
add it into my to-do list every day i
start to feel guilt when i don't
so it creates stress when i just don't
get it done and then you got you have to
like be like
do i need this every day and you have to
make that decision
and i'm always making those decisions
like does this need to be a daily thing
anymore and it turned out to not be and
i've been
continuing like my process my my growth
has continued even though i'm not doing
it every day
and so like like sometimes there's
correla causation that isn't there it's
just like there's some correlation but
it's not
it's not like integral that you do
everything and it's very easy to lock
into like
i have to do all these things baseball
was the big thing too i'd be like i have
to do
all this workout stuff or i won't pitch
good and it's just that's not
the connection wasn't that strong
between those two things
um and letting go of a bunch of crap
they just didn't need to be doing
um was like it was a huge part of like
my journey
uh because i was just like i learned all
this stuff about like arm care and
how to stay healthy and how to like get
enough rest and all stuff when i was
young in the early in the professional
baseball
and then as i got older i was like
it was the hardest thing to start
shedding stuff where i was like i need
to spend less energy every day and i can
focus more on just like chilling because
the only thing that matters is
the the 10 minutes i'm on the mound now
like that
i could do if i did nothing all day and
i still and it made me feel good
and went out there and i accomplished
well because i had so much brain energy
that's what i needed to do i was gonna
do that no matter what my teammates
thought of me sitting in my locker all
day
right and that's that's another thing
that again like i said my keys are like
what are people thinking what are they
what's the reinforcement i'm getting
from other people
that's just big for me it still is to
this day always will be
it's never going to go away i'm just
going to learn different ways to deal
with it and it's going to become less
important probably but
it's never going to go away and letting
go of that stuff is my con
is still process here's one thing i'm
really interested to see
i'm probably going to be on another team
this year probably that isn't the twins
i've been with the twins my whole career
i'm gonna be on with a group of guys
that they're probably a couple guys i
actually know or played with before
on the team for the most part there
won't be i'm gonna go through the cycle
again like what's everyone think of me
like it's gonna happen i know that
and it's weird because i'm coming in as
a little bit of a big dog a little bit
of a free
free agent like veteran i've had a lot
more experience on other guys
and coming to that realization is a
weird transition i'm in right now where
i'm like i'm not the young rookie guy
anymore i'm the
i'm the i need to lead um and that's
that's really interesting but again
i know that like self-awareness and
process and purpose is gonna get me
through it it's just gonna be another
it's like another stage i'm going
through which is
like i said i'm aware that it's gonna
happen already and it hasn't yet so
that's
that's you know that's one way of
getting through it that's the one thing
you got to do
that's the start right there yeah it's
it's cool that you
you have an awareness of it now but
you're not stressed about it like this
is just what i do
this is the thing that i'm gonna have to
go up against when this thing comes
along
yeah and i think that's a place of power
you know when your mind's always you
know in the future being stressed about
something
you're anxious about something you don't
always have to be anxious about you're
like okay yeah
this thing's happening and no i can't
control all the outcomes no i can't
control what they think about me
but what can i control i can i can focus
on me i can show up
uh i can give things power i can wear
the suit that i need to wear
you know um also if you you know don't
give away
your bread and butter but uh do you have
any like prospects where you
might end up i mean you're living in
seattle right now that's
i actually to be honest i literally have
nothing i got nothing for you
uh i'll just say there's been a lot of
teams kind of in the mix just like
reaching out and there's a lot of
feelers and stuff
um it's just this year with the covid
and with the shortened season and
everything worked it's just going to be
it might slow play a little bit
um but you know free agency is always
like a domino's falling thing because
when guys sign less guys are available
unless
teams have less prospects to fill their
holes so like
basically right now only a like two or
three guys have
have signed i don't think any relievers
have signed anywhere so like once that
first domino falls
they kind of like people the teams start
to get a little bit more
um serious about their offers and about
like actually putting them
dollars on on things and actually
putting like numbers of years
and uh but you know i we're we're happy
on in my camp
just about like the the people who've
reached out they said they're interested
and
uh kind of watching how things go and
i'm just gonna be patient with it
to be honest there's the amount of
stress that's attached to it
isn't isn't as much as i thought it
would be simply because
like frankly my career on the way that
pay scaling works and stuff i got
surgery my first year of arbitration
which is when your pay is supposed to
start going up
which means that like that first year
when i came off like instead of like
doubling it like went up like 10
and so and that starts to scale so then
you scale off of that for your next year
so like
the number's always lower than it could
have been so i'd like for the last four
years i've made less money that i could
have done had i not got hurt four years
ago
like and that's just the way it is so
but i've accepted it
worked with so now i'm not so worried
about like eeking out every dollar i can
in this thing i'm just i'm because i
know that whatever it is i'm like
i'm happy with that i'm good with that
let's go and i'm gonna make the best of
it and i'm going to go out and i'm going
to compete
because that's the one thing i care
about i can't care about going out
following my process competing
regardless of how much money i'm making
and that's just the way that
it's been up to this point while at the
same time knowing that this is your
opportunity to make as much money as you
can
uh so that you can retire and like be
with your family when you want to retire
and be with your family you're not like
oh i need more money
like that's not a situation that anyone
wants to be in right really they're
extending
retirement or whatever they're extending
they're working past the time they
wanted to work past because they don't
have enough money
that's that that's the only thing that
i'm keeping
in in the back of my mind but uh no it's
been good uh
i i you know who knows uh yeah
seattle could be in there who knows like
yeah
life could change a lot i've lived two
different two different stages of my
life uh off and on you know
spring to spring to fall over and over
and over again for going this will be my
14th spring training
which is mine that's modeling yeah um
that's so cool though dude that's
i mean congrats it's just so cool it's
thanks
like you've really you've accomplished a
lot you've done really well thank you
yeah uh it's i i imagine the
i imagine it's pretty weird so you
you've definitely you've played since
cove it's been around right like you've
played
in weird situations like where you have
to wear a mask in the dugout or
or what is it like yeah masking the
dugout mask in the bullpen
uh only time we're not wearing a mask is
out on the field um
uh we have our like our own rows that
rosenberg we're supposed to run out to
the mound with and take with us like i
didn't i didn't do that one time didn't
run out with my rosin bag effort i just
like i'm not using this i don't
it's stupid there's a lot of dumb stuff
that sucks uh we wore a mask
all day if we were inside we had to have
it on every moment
besides eating um yeah and you know that
i
i you know i understand it's just it you
know it's annoying wearing it like
you're sitting there and you guys are
like three feet apart really
yeah one of us gets this dudes like yeah
it's it's all this
you know it's really this silly game
that we're all playing and we're all
super aware of where it's at we're all
you know
i mean you know there's some extent
depending on what news media you're
watching like there's there's some
people who um
you know and i have compassion for them
like they're actually they're still
legitimately terrified like they're
you know there's a lot of people who
haven't even like left their houses
since this whole thing started and
you know i definitely have compassion
for them but we're all kind of just
we're we're playing with the hands that
were dealt and uh
you know i'm glad you guys are still
making it happen though you guys are
still out there you know it must be
weird with no
um i i don't consume a ton of sports
when i'm watching but
i still haven't adjusted to seeing like
when you watch nba or watch football
yeah when they have no fans where they
have like the computer monitors or
like like the ellen degeneres show just
has like a bunch of vertical tv screens
and it's so strange to me um but we're
all
we're rolling with the punches man yeah
yeah it's just
again it's like it's it's it's what we
got to do and and and
with with how it's going like like
yesterday it was like 150 000
like i mean
assuming the presidential transition
happens
we could just like president joe could
just be like four
four weeks guys everything's shut down
everything's closed
and we're just gonna hemorrhage money to
take care of you why we can and we're
gonna see if we can
at least stamp this thing down to ten
thousand cases a day instead of you know
instead of a hundred and fifty thousand
um and if that's what we gotta do that's
what we gotta do but you know
i'm anticipating our season next year
being uh being affected
uh but at the same time i think we
proved that
even because it's been it's been worse
since we started playing like in terms
of cases and deaths and everything it's
been worse the whole time than it was
when we were shut down
so like we've proven that we can play
and avoid it to an extent
um and be healthy to an extent i'm still
like it's all
again it's like messaging so if we if
we're playing and the message world
countrywide is like guys we're not going
anywhere do anything then i'm much more
i'm much more comfortable playing
because again i'm worried more about the
message that i'm sending
than me actually getting sick yeah um
because i feel like dude i
you know i sit and stream and play video
games all day like yeah i have no
problem
sitting in my house just tell me i'll do
it uh i just i just really want the
messaging to be there and so the people
are
are gonna take care of this thing when
it gets done but
you know we'll uh we'll see where we go
from here but yeah
it's been weird but it is what it is
what it is and
we you know people got to work yeah no
exactly
you guys are handling it well you're
doing your work um so
outside of covet you know it's there is
the unpredictability factor with all of
it
we don't know exactly what's going next
but um
let's let's just uh kind of give the
people what do you
what do you have going on in your life
like what do you have going on um
like what's your future plans here um
yeah so tons of i have a thousand
billion projects going at any given time
um i'm working on um developing a couple
continuing to develop two my two youtube
channels one one is just
built around gaming and and
entertainment content that's not
baseball related basically so
um there's like pokemon card opening
packs on there now and i'm doing another
one of those videos
by the way that's like the most fun
thing in the world i didn't know that
when i was nine all the thing i wanted
to do in the world is have a couple
hundred bucks to spend on them so that i
could open them all at once
i have 75 packs sitting behind me that i
cannot wait to open i'm jealous
uh can you facetime me while you open
this uh i'm gonna be live on stream so
if you wanna watch it bro
i'll check it out then it'll be there uh
and
so that's i'm trevor may on on youtube
and then i have trevor may baseball
which i'm actually
just bought some equipment i'm gonna do
some pitch design which is a whole new
like new age thing in baseball
uh where you watch like 10 000 frame
rate
frames per second like slow motion of
like how pitches come out of your hand
and stuff
you try to practice um oh my goodness
i'm so sorry
i might have to do a little editing on
this thing i'm sorry she's yelling
though i didn't want to
want the catches to be in the background
of the whole thing um
uh and uh so trevor maybe baseball's
gonna be having some of that stuff
um you know there's a lot of the podcast
stuff that you've heard
um has been a little bit more tailored
i've done some videos
uh about you know mindset and like
getting sleep and
wrestling relaxation how important that
is um when you're playing games every
day
all kinds of stuff and i'm looking at
planning a lot more of that stuff out uh
my team
because i'm getting the point now where
there's like a there needs to be a team
around me
um i have a youtube editor now full time
almost full time um we're getting close
to where he's about like i'm about to
hire him away from his job
uh and i have a graphic designer who
does like all my social media my
thumbnails and stuff
um and i'm looking to hire a assistant i
have 200
applications on assistant job so i'm
currently trying to find that
what a cool place to be in though yeah
it's bro
hiring someone like that has something
i've never done so i'm i'm
i'm having fun with that process but it
is time consuming
and then uh i actually started a project
called um with a
a startup called fan control football uh
which
anyone who plays fantasy football wishes
like making decisions
about the game actually affected the
game like that's their premise
so like the game's gonna be broadcast
live it's like arena football seven-man
football
uh like a lot of d1 athletes and stuff
that aren't in the nfl are gonna play in
it like this would be like a colin kelly
might might enjoy this i think
uh and the fans like vote on your
starting lineup and they vote
on the playbook you're gonna use and
they vote on
uh uh you know like a half time you vote
on like if you're gonna put your other
running back in or not like if they
match up
and the fans and like i'm an owner of a
team and so we're gonna live watch it
and then i'm gonna have to like direct
and i'm gonna be the coaches too
it's gonna be super cool they're gonna
add in a bunch of stuff really cool
premise
never done before it i i'm really
excited to see where it goes um
and then so and then i have my own
podcast called the may contain action
podcast
built around content creation um
tackling a lot of
uh a lot of like current events in the
content space on twitch and youtube and
whatever but
in reality the biggest thing we do is we
bring on a creator
who has had a path to wherever they're
doing whether they're doing full time or
have hard time whatever
and we just try to glean uh wisdom from
from how they got to where they are
uh and because because it's become such
a hot topic there's so many kids that
are like
like being a youtuber is like rivaling
being a professional athlete like in
terms of what kids want to do
um and so and there's a lot of mistakes
and a lot of things that
a lot of mindsets out there they're a
little bit toxic to achieving that goal
um like worried about numbers and stuff
that's like a whole new thing the new
generation's gonna
like they're starting to connect with
their self-worth very young
and yeah and it's it's a again
the really really really successful
content creators they're all process
oriented they're all growth mindset
um and then there's the people who do it
and got into a size
and that's okay for them too the same
thing like they were growth until
they're like i'm cool with the growth
side of things and now i just want to
build my community but again that the
pro the purpose just changed
right so everything we just talked about
in like a content creation type of a
framework and then we
you know we it's a little bit of a radio
show we like play a game at the end and
we
we shout out some other creators that we
enjoy and that you know because
everyone's in their own little clicks
and stuff and yeah so you get this
it's got good discoverability it's
pretty funny uh
we're sponsored by manscape so we get to
read all the weird stuff about shaving
your balls
that's cool excellent so that's a great
that's a great show and i recommend if
you if you watch streaming streams or
taking youtube at all like you might
discover someone hilarious in there
um and it's it's a really good time and
then uh yeah i'm always live streaming
on twitch i'm trevor mann twitch
uh that content is starting to vary like
wildly um to be honest there's no video
game where i'm like waking up every
morning like
let's go so it's like i'm open pokemon
cards i'm gonna do a tick tock reaction
stream on sunday which
because i love tick tocks and i sit
there and i laugh at them all day i'm
like people need to watch me laugh
yes people need to laugh with me like
all i want to do is show people these
so i'm going to get my favorites i'm
going to have checking me their
favorites we're going to just like
go through them and i'm just going to
give them thumbs up the thumbs downs
like simon cowell and it's going to be
fun we'll see
well we'll see how it works but uh and
that'll go on youtube so it's all it's
all connected and
and i'm just super interested in like
how this all works man and
it's something that i think that fits
really well into my personality and
things i enjoy
so yeah and then you know the other
big project navigating through free
agency so i'm doing all this at the same
time
but those are the big ones uh those are
the things that i really really want to
be
that i'm really really striving to like
uh be purposeful with and create
uh good attainable goals and you know
create value for the other people
involved
my my co-host uh paul action jackson
is the co-host may contain action as you
can hear in the name um
he's a full-time creator and uh it's
i've said this to him a few times but
it's really important to me that people
that do this full-time like year-round
when i play with them or something i
want to create more value for them than
they're creating for me because i'm not
full-time
this is their livelihood so anything
anytime that i can like
i don't know bring any sort of
opportunity or give any sort of like
idea to or or something to someone else
i really really want it to work
not only for you know putting on youtube
and seeing how it does but also like
giving them an opportunity to like
expand off it too uh so
that's anyone i work with like that's
that's my gary vee-ism i don't know
cannot wait to meet him in person my one
of my big purpose goals when a big life
goal is to get on his podcast and and be
in that that office in new york and
i believe that you got that shoot uh we
we know each other actually
we've reinteracted quite quite a bit so
it'll happen but uh
you know it's all about just creating
value for other people and that's all
that stuff
that's outside of the baseball world is
is uh is really really really kind of
the ethos and
i think it's i think it's served me well
i think it's like you said it's powerful
yeah dude i mean you're doing it for me
right here you know you just just by
coming on the podcast on my podcast and
and having this combo for me you're
really you know
lending out your your voice to the
people who are on my end so
it's very cool the content creation
world is
such a community you know it's uh i
working in the hip-hop world a lot i
feel like i would notice how much
unnecessary competitiveness there is
it's like oh like
you're using that program so i'm going
to use it or it's like dude like
give away your juice like bring people
in on your juice
like let let like like let let people in
with you it's not this is not a
competition it's not me versus you
it's like we could lift each other up
together you know especially with this
content creation world um
we are we're about out of time trevor
but i was um
i just wanted to kind of end on the word
legacy
it's something that i don't know if you
think about more as you get older
or if you're i'm sure it's probably
pretty pretty much in the forefront of
your mind but
do you ever think about like what legacy
you want to to not only leave
before you go but the legacy
that you want to communicate as you're
still like in your day to day everything
you're doing like what do you want
to inspire people by what's what's the
legacy that you think of like what
people hear trevor may what do you want
them to think about
dude that is an awesome end question i i
want to steal that
really bad but uh
dude um that is that that's a huge gary
v ism right like it's the whole
without so you you so i i think about it
this way there's a lot of people
um there's kind of two camps and and the
word legacy
means two things when it's in a
non-religious standpoint
you know when it's in a non-like
creating spreading goodness going ahead
you know like
things like that uh it's it's it's
almost assumption like when i'm gone i'm
gonna be gone
um but my memory is what the
the memory of me the legacy that i leave
is is gonna be the most valuable thing i
ever did
um and that puts a lot of like
oomph in it that puts a lot of value and
like like importance to it
um and that for me that could be scary
but it's also very exciting
and so in terms of legacy man i
i want to value is very important
because
i i create i say the use the word value
because the things that i enjoy so much
are entertainment our performance and
our like evoking thought and and
thoughtfulness
and mindfulness and uh thinking in the
moment and
being self-aware like that's those are
like my things that i
value extremely highly in my own life um
they have got me
they've they've given to me over and
over and over again
working through obstacles and and
proceeding to work towards my goals and
my purpose
so the the overarching purpose is going
to be
uh um i create value for other peoples
and their paths and i want them to
to to be able to look at what i've done
and who i am and what i say
apply to their own lives and then
achieve their own purpose like that's
legacy i want i want
that value even if it's never even if
it's no one i've ever talked to
personally
directed to that at all but they hear
what i say and they hear it in their own
way
they apply to their own lives and it's
it helps in any way shape or form
them achieve what they believe their
purpose is that's the ultimate legacy
for me
so if even if they can't even say trevor
may help me get here even if they don't
realize that i even had a
point of it doesn't matter that's value
that has been
added to another person's life either
advertently or inadvertently
and that is what i'm on this earth to do
wow in my opinion
i love that dude that's so great so i
feel like i got like like chills halfway
i was like yes
yes yes i'm gonna be honest i don't
think i've ever gotten
that concise and that clear with it so
that might been that might have been the
first time i ever even
really really got it like out that
clearly but i want to i want to i want
to add value to people's lives
that allow them to achieve their own
purpose uh and help um
in a way shape or form and it's just so
everything i do and and
it's it's something i'm grappling with
all the time i'm only 31 i don't have
kids yet
but when i have kids that's the thing i
want more than anything them to know
better than anything even when they're
barely able to speak i want them to know
that they're going to have a purpose
they don't know what it is
but they're going to be looking for it
and while they're looking for it and
then as they
as they realize what it is whether it's
playing the piano whether it's being an
athlete
whether it's literally just being a
husband being a dad being
whatever that purpose is and they
determine what it is i'm going to
support that
and help them give them the tools to
work through their process to get there
uh as well as i possibly can and and
if i have a son that thinks the same way
and wants to leave the same legacy as me
i want him to build on the things i
already have and make it even a thousand
times better
because who knows you know who knows in
40 years what what we'll know about the
brain and
and you know streamlining this whole
process and getting to the growth
mindset faster because you know to be
honest i didn't
see it in this light until i was in my
20s
and i wish i would have and you you
there's 12 year olds out you're talking
like dude this kid gets it
yes he's gonna be a prodigy that's what
they are they just they figure this out
process purpose early earlier and
earlier and earlier so
um if i could leave anybody with that is
find that purpose man
and then and use the steps and and it
might be worded differently in your head
but the gist is there man it's the same
it's the same
it's the same top bottom left right
center yeah
wow dude that's beautiful that's a
wonderful way to end the podcast um
listeners definitely check out all of
trevor's channels uh we'll go ahead and
i'll include those in the description
um trevor this was super great man i
really appreciate you doing this for me
i'm really appreciate you
appreciate you taking time out of your
day to have this convo and kind of
uh mind you for all the good stuff here
and uh
dude if you ever want to if you ever
want to pull out those cdjs and
do some mixing maybe we can do some dj
stuff together that would be
that'd be fun man that'd be really fun
yeah we should do it maybe i'll maybe
i'll check up there one of these days
i'm still just down in longview right
now so
uh not that far yeah it's really not um
all right man we'll we'll go ahead and
end this uh listeners
have a good rest of your day if you
haven't drank water today what are you
doing man drink some water
uh if you haven't stretched today you
got to stretch it out you got to get
your body moving
believe in yourself find your purpose
discipline self-awareness there's a lot
of great gold nuggets in this so you
know listen to it again and again it's
great
trevor thanks again man thanks for
having me
[Music]
knowledge is power
you